RAHUL MULCHANDANI

London, UK | 07879681742 | mulcharv@gmail.com | Portfolio Site

PROFILE

I am a fullstack software engineer who has proven experience writing responsive front-end components via React and Typescript, as well as performant REST APIs with Node, Express, MongoDB, and PSQL. With management experience across multiple technical disciplines, I am able to work seamlessly with various teams to achieve collective business goals as a developer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Frontend: Javasript, React.js, Typescript, MUI, Formik, Yup, HTML5, CSS, React Query, React Router, Shadon, Auth0
- Backend: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Jest, SuperTest, PassportJS
- Tools: Git, Github, NPM, Vite

PROJECTS

SeatSwap - Link FE Github | BE Github

- · Developing a peer-to-peer platform enabling travellers on budget flights to swap seats, eliminating seat selection fees.
- · Creating a robust back-end API using Node.js and Express, leveraging Jest and Supertest for comprehensive testing.
- Implementing a front-end using TypeScript with React and React Query, and authorization via Autho.

Trading App- Link | FE Github | BE Github

- · Created a full-stack mock retail trading application for users to buy and sell stocks for gains and losses
- · Built a RESTful ExpressJS API that calls on the Marketstack API to deliver current stock data to a React front-end
- · Integrated current stock price to calculate unrealised gains and losses and update portfolio value

Blog App - Link | FE Github | BE Github

- · Designed a full-stack blogging application for users to blog and comment on the London music scene
- Developed a RESTful ExpressJS API, with a React front-end where visitors can post and login (via PassportJS)

Shopping Cart - Link | Github

- Built a React front-end mock merchandise store application for the NBA franchise Toronto Raptors
- · Delivered the information of user cart items between components through prop drilling state

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer CargoLogix 2024 - Present

- Building reusable React components styled with MUI, managing state via Redux, and creating Formik forms
- · Collaborating in an Agile environment, I solve complex problems, contribute to feature planning, and review code
- Working on a platform that combines cargo bidding, load management, and financial tracking into one place

Account Manager

IDM Professional Corporation CPA

2019 - Present

- Managed a team of 4 employees to develop corporate and personal tax returns correctly
- Implemented software solutions to streamline bookkeeping, trained team members on solutions
- · Troubleshoot bugs in tax applications and collaborated with developers of software companies to resolve them

Production Manager

Salflex Polymers

2017 - 2019

- · Managed the production cycle of automotive plastics from raw material input to finished product
- · Implemented a continuous improvement of varying raw material inputs to achieve a continuous product deployment

3D Laser Scanning Technician

TSC Inc.

2016 - 2017

- · Conducted laser scans of buildings and used collected data to design fascia panels
- · Used Grasshopper software to build generative algorithms for 3D panel geometry, increased workflow efficiency

EDUCATION

Hamilton, ON McMaster University 2011 - 2016

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering.